SUSAN EVANS

UX Designer + Developer

susanev.com hello@susanev.com (206) 395-8146

Three years experience leading UX design and research. Seven years experience innovating in the computer science education space.

I am passionate about improving the human experience by combining deep technical and design knowledge to craft digital experiences.

I love solving challenging problems in diverse teams while using user-centered practices.

WORK EXPERIENCE

User Experience Developer

Premera

Jan 2017 – Present

Leading a number of UX initiatives to improve the member experience, and the upcoming redesign. My process includes sketching, high-fidelity code prototypes, and research informed iteration.

User Experience Designer

University of Washington LiY!

Feb 2014 - Mar 2016

Led the design and research of a tool for faculty across the nation to use when creating workshops focused on the advancement of women and underrepresented groups in engineering fields.

Computer Science Instructor

Ada Developers Academy

Nov 2016 - Present

Design and teach a series of Ruby classes for students with limited prior programming experience. Create a safe and inclusive, learning community centered around students.

University of Washington

Mar 2016 – Present

Design and teach undergraduate and graduate introductory programming courses using a variety of languages including Java, Processing and p5.js.

SKILLS

Design & Research	Programming
Rapid prototyping	Java
Interaction design	Python
Survey Design	Ruby on Rails
Interviews	HTML & CSS
Usability studies	JavaScript

EDUCATION

University of Washington

MS in Human Centered Design & Engineering Graduated Jun 2016

University of Arizona

BS in Computer Science and Mathematics Graduated Dec 2008